bikerumor.com 2019-07-07

# Privacy Policy - Bikerumor

We take your privacy seriously. This policy describes what personal information we collect and how we use it. This privacy policy is applicable to bikerumor.com, triathlonrumor.com, bikerumortechshop.com and any other website owned or operated by BikeBoardMedia, Inc. (hereafter BBM).

**Routine Information Collection & Storage**

All web servers track basic information about their visitors. This information includes, but is not limited to, IP addresses, browser details, timestamps and referring pages. None of this information can personally identify specific visitors to this site. The information is tracked for routine administration and maintenance purposes, and lets me know what pages and information are useful and helpful to visitors.

This site collects a name, email address and IP address for each comment left on any post. This information is stored on our servers, and we make reasonable efforts at securing our and your information. Viewing and use of any BBM-owned website is at your own risk. BBM is not responsible for disclosure of your personal information due to accident, theft, acts of God or other mischievous or illegal behavior. We may make any or all personal information available to appropriate authorities as required by law. We also suggest you review our [Comments Policy](http://bikerumor.com/comments-policy).

**The Type of Information the Service Collects**

The following Privacy Policy summarizes the various ways we treat personally identifiable and other information about you and your computer, mobile or other device when you access, visit and/or use the Service. This Privacy Policy does not cover information collected elsewhere, including without limitation offline and on sites, applications, destinations, or services linked to from the Service.

The Service generally collects personally identifiable information with your specific knowledge and consent. For instance, when you enter a sweepstakes or contest, complete a survey, make a purchase, subscribe to our publication(s), register for certain services, or register and/or set up an account/profile to access, visit and/or use certain portions of the Service, or the Service as a whole, you may be provided, or required to choose, a password and/or User ID, and you may provide a credit, debit, or charge card number, or other payment information, as well as your name, telephone number(s), email and/or street address, and other personally identifiable information. Other information such as your age, gender, an avatar, and the number for your mobile or other device may also be requested. In addition, you may be asked to send us similar information via messaging (e.g., email, SMS, MMS, or other technologies). All such information shall be referred to in this Privacy Policy as your “Registration Information”.

Our servers may also automatically collect information about you, your online behavior and your computer, mobile or other device. The information collected may include, without limitation, the make, model, settings, specifications (e.g., CPU speed, connection speed, browser type, operating system, device identifier) and geographic location of you and/or your computer, mobile or other device, as well as date/time stamp, IP address, pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, the site(s), application(s), destination(s), and/or service(s) you arrived from, and other clickstream data.

If you choose to access, visit and/or use any third party social networking service(s) that may be integrated with the Service, we may receive personally identifiable information and other information about you and your computer, mobile or other device that you have made available to those services, including information about your contacts on those services. For example, some social networking services allow you to push content from our Service to your contacts or to pull information about your contacts so you can connect with them on or through our Service. Some social networking services also will facilitate your registration for our Service or enhance or personalize your experience on our Service. Your decision to use a social networking service in connection with our Service is voluntary. However, you should make sure you are comfortable with the information your third party social networking services may make available to our Service by visiting those services’ privacy policies and/or modifying your privacy settings directly with those services. We reserve the right to use, transfer, assign, sell, share, and provide access to all personally identifiable information and other information about you and your computer, mobile or other device that we receive through third-party social networking services in the same ways described in this Agreement as all of your other information.  

**Information Collection and Use**

Certain categories of information collected are necessary to use our Services, such as the information you must provide when registering for some Services. We may collect and combine information when you interact with our services including information outlined below

Information that you provide to us. We collect the information you provide to us in order to enable us to operate and provide our Services, including:  
When you create an account. (please note that, when you use our Services, we may recognize you or your devices even if you are not signed in to our Services.)  
We may use device IDs, cookies and other signals, including information obtained from third parties, to associate accounts and/or devices with you.  
When you use our Services to communicate with others or post, upload or store content (such as comments, photos, voice inputs, videos, emails, messaging services and attachments).

When you otherwise use our Services, such as view the content that we make available, perform search queries or install any software we provide such as plug-ins. When you sign up for paid Services, use Services that require your financial information or complete transactions with us or our business partners, we may collect your payment and billing information in order to provide you with those paid Services. We may remember the payment information that you entered during a prior purchase for paid Services and provide you with the option to use that payment information during the purchase of a new product. 

Device information. We collect information from your devices (computers, mobile phones, tablets, etc.) in order to provide you with our Services, including information about how you interact with our Services and those of our third-party partners and information that allows us to recognize and associate your activity across devices and Services. This information includes device-specific identifiers and information such as IP address, cookie information, mobile device and advertising identifiers, browser version, operating system type and version, mobile network information, device settings and software data. 

Location information. We collect location information from a variety of sources. 

Information from cookies and other technologies.  
We collect information when you access content, advertising, sites, interactive widgets, applications and other products (both on and off our Services) where our data collection technologies (such as web beacons, development tools, cookies and other technologies, etc.) are present. These data collection technologies allow us to understand your activity on and off our Services and to collect and store information when you interact with Services we offer to partners.

This information includes the kind of content or ads served, viewed or clicked on; the frequency and duration of your activities; the sites or apps you used before accessing our Services and where you went next; whether you engaged with specific content or ads; and whether you went on to visit an advertiser’s website, downloaded an advertiser’s app, purchased a product or service advertised or took other actions. 

Information from others. We collect information about you when we receive it from other users, third parties and affiliates, such as: 

When you connect your account to third-party services or sign in using a third-party partner (such as Facebook or Twitter).

From publicly available sources.

From advertisers about your experiences or interactions with their offerings.

When we obtain information from third parties or other companies, such as those that use our Services. This may include your activity on other sites and apps as well as information that those third parties provide to you or us. 

**How We Use Information Provided**

We mainly rely on three separate bases to lawfully process your information. First, we need to process your information in certain ways to provide our Services to you. This processing of your information for the purposes of personalized content and ads is a necessary part of the Services we provide. Second, where you have given us consent to use your information in certain ways, we will rely on your consent. Third, as described in more detail below, in certain cases, we may process your information where necessary to further our legitimate interests, where those legitimate interests are not overridden by your rights or interests. Occasionally, we may rely on other legal bases to process your information such as to protect a user’s vital interests (such as where there is a risk of imminent harm) or to comply with a legal obligation. 

In order to deliver, personalize and improve our Services, we combine and use the information that we have about you (including information we receive on and off our Services) to understand how you use and interact with our Services and the people or things that you’re connected to and interested in. We may also use the information we have about you in the following ways and for the following purposes:

To provide, maintain, improve and develop relevant features, content and Services. 

To analyze your content and other information (including incoming and outgoing emails, instant messages, posts photos, attachments and other communications) in order to keep our Services safe and secure.This analysis also assists us in making the content, Services and ads we provide to you more personalized. You can review and control certain types of information tied to your account by contacting us.

To fulfill your requests and when authorized by you. 

To help advertisers and publishers connect to offer relevant advertising in their apps and websites.

To match and serve targeted advertising (across devices and both on and off our Services) and provide targeted advertising based on your device activity, inferred interests and location information.

To contact you with information about your account or with marketing messages, which you can also control. 

To associate your activity across our Services and your different devices as well as associate any accounts you may use across our Services together. We may associate activity and accounts under a single user ID.

To carry out or support promotions.

To conduct research and support innovation. 

To create analytics and reports for external parties, including partners, publishers, advertisers, apps, third parties and the public regarding the use of and trends within our Services and ads, including showing trends to partners regarding general preferences, the effectiveness of ads and information on user experiences. These analytics and reports may include aggregate or pseudonymised information, but do not include any information relating to an identified or identifiable user.

To provide location-based Services, advertising, search results and other content consistent with your location settings.

To combine information that we have about you with information that we obtain from business partners or other companies, such as your activities on other sites and apps in order to ensure that the ads, Services and content we provide to you are more suited to your interests.

To detect and defend against fraudulent, abusive or unlawful activity and to keep our Services safe and secure.

We provide you with controls to manage your experience with us. For example, you can review or edit your account information, manage your marketing preferences or opt out of targeted ads. While personalized ads are necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests and are a necessary part of our agreement with you, we offer you the ability to object to certain personalized ads through your choices to opt out of certain targeted ads. If you object through this opt-out, you will continue to see ads, but they may not be as relevant or useful to you. 

**How We Share Information Provided**

BBM shares information within its affiliated brands and companies. We also share information we have about you in accordance with this Privacy Policy, including to provide Services that you have requested (including when you connect to third-party apps and widgets). We do not sell, license or share information that individually identifies our customers with companies, organizations or individuals outside of BBM unless one of the following circumstances applies:

With your consent. We will share information with companies, organisations or individuals outside of Oath when we have your consent. 

Within BBM. Information may also be shared within BBM, including with other BBM Services and affiliates. BBM affiliates may use the information in a manner consistent with their privacy policies.

With partners. We may share your information with non-affiliated companies who are:

Trusted partners. We provide user information to trusted partners who work on behalf of BBM based on our directions and in compliance with appropriate confidentiality measures.

Advertising, analytics and business partners (limited to non-personally identifiable information). We may share aggregated or pseudonymous information (including demographic information) with partners, such as publishers, advertisers, measurement analytics, apps or other companies. For example, we may tell an advertiser how its ads performed or report how many people installed an app after seeing a promotion. We do not share information that personally identifies you (personally identifiable information includes your name or email address) with these partners, such as publishers, advertisers, measurement analytics, apps or other companies. 

When you use third-party apps, websites or other products integrated with our Services, they may collect information about your activities subject to their own terms and privacy policies. 

We allow other companies that show advertisements on our web pages or apps to collect information from your browsers or devices. Other companies’ use of cookies and other data collection technologies are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Like many companies, we may allow cookie matching with selected partners. However, these parties are not authorized to access BBM cookies.

For legal purposes. We may access, preserve and disclose information to investigate, prevent or take action in connection with: (i) legal processes, and legal and governmental agency requests; (ii) enforcement of the Terms; (iii) claims that any content violates the rights of third parties; (iv) requests for customer service; (v) technical issues; (v) protecting the rights, property or personal safety of BBM, its users or the public; (vi) establishing or exercising our legal rights or defending against legal claims; or (vii) as otherwise required by law. This may include responding to lawful governmental requests.

New ownership. If the ownership or control of all or part of BBM or a specific Service changes as a result of a merger, acquisition or sale of assets, we may transfer your information to the new owner.

**Specific Products and Services**

Information security and data retention – Oath has technical, administrative and physical safeguards in place to help protect against unauthorized access, use or disclosure of customer information that we collect or store. BBM will retain your information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with the Services. If you no longer want BBM to use your information to provide you with the Services, you can close your account and BBM will delete the information it holds about you unless BBM needs to retain and use your information to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes or to enforce our agreements. 

**Legitimate Interests**

BBM may use your information to provide, improve and customize our Services and the ads and content that we serve to you. This may include the sharing of your information for such purposes as is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests and your legitimate interests in receiving personalized content and services. Using and sharing your information for such purposes is also necessary to enable us to pursue our legitimate interests of understanding how our Services are being used and of developing ways to change our Services so they are more exciting and interesting for you and other users. Using your information for the reasons described in this Privacy Policy is also necessary to allow us to pursue our legitimate interests of improving our Services, obtaining insights into usage patterns of our Services, efficiency and interest of our Services for users. 

BBM may also use your information for safety and security purposes, including the sharing of your information for such purposes as is necessary to pursue our and your legitimate interests of ensuring the security of our Services, including enhancing users’ protection against harassment, IP infringement, spam, and crime and security risks of all types.

You have the right to object to any of this processing and, if you want to object, please contact us.

**Protecting Children’s Privacy**

Our Services are for a general audience. We do not knowingly collect, use or share information that could reasonably be used to identify children under the age of 16 without prior parental consent or consistent with applicable law. With parental permission, a child under the age of 16 might have a BBM family account.

**Data Processing and Transfers**

When you use or interact with any of our Services, you consent to the data processing, sharing, transferring and uses of your information as outlined in this Privacy Policy. Regardless of the country where you reside, you authorize us to transfer, process, store and use your information in countries other than your own in accordance with this Privacy Policy and to provide you with Services. Some of these countries may not have the same data protection safeguards as the country where you reside. 

BBM may process information related to individuals in the EU/EEA and may transfer that information from the EU/EEA through various compliance mechanisms, including data processing agreements based on the EU/EEA Standard Contractual Clauses. By using our Services, you consent to us transferring information about you to these countries.

BBM is part of a global service and so shares information with affiliates and other companies based outside the European Economic Area (‘EEA’) for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. 

The United States and other non-EEA countries have different laws on data protection and rules in relation to government access to information. If you are based in the EEA, when your data is moved from your home country to a third country outside the EEA, some of these countries may not have the same data protection safeguards as your home country. 

To the extent that BBM is deemed to transfer information about you outside the EEA, Oath relies separately, alternatively and independently on the following legal bases to transfer your information: 

Standard contractual clauses. The European Commission has adopted standard contractual clauses that provide safeguards for personal data that is transferred outside the EEA. We use these clauses when transferring personal data outside the EEA including to our affiliates. 

Contractual necessity. You can choose whether or not you want to use our Services. However, if you want to use our Services, you need to agree to our Terms of Service, which set out the terms of the contract between us and you. As we operate in countries worldwide (including in the United States) and use technical infrastructure in these countries, to be able to deliver our Services to you in accordance with the contract between us, we may need to transfer your information to other jurisdictions where necessary. We can’t provide you with our Services without moving your data around the world. 

Privacy Shield. Some companies to which we may transfer your information in the United States may be certified to receive your information under the Privacy Shield program.

**Additional Important Information**

This Privacy Policy applies only to BBM. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that BBM does not own or control, or to people that BBM does not employ or manage. In addition, some affiliated products may have different privacy policies and practices that are not subject to this Privacy Policy. 

**Edits**

We may amend or update this Privacy Policy from time to time, so you should check it periodically. If we make edits of a material nature, we will provide you with appropriate notice before such changes take effect. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

Where necessary, this site uses cookies to store information about a visitor’s preferences and history in order to better serve the visitor and/or present the visitor with customized content.

Advertising partners and other third parties may also use cookies, scripts and/or web beacons to track visitors to our site in order to display advertisements and other useful information. Such tracking is done directly by the third parties through their own servers and is subject to their own privacy policies.

**Controlling Your Privacy**

Note that you can change your browser settings to disable cookies if you have privacy concerns. Disabling cookies for all sites is not recommended as it may interfere with your use of some sites. The best option is to disable or enable cookies on a per-site basis. Consult your browser documentation for instructions on how to block cookies and other tracking mechanisms.

**Special Notes About Google Advertising**

Any advertisements served by Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Google advertising services. [Learn how to opt out of Google’s cookie usage](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). As mentioned above, any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google’s own privacy policies. Additionally, BBM has implemented Google Analytics features that relate to Display Advertising (e.g., Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration, or Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting). Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

About Google advertising: What is the DoubleClick DART cookie? The DoubleClick DART cookie is used by Google in the ads served on publisher websites displaying AdSense for content ads. When users visit an AdSense publisher’s website and either view or click on an ad, a cookie may be dropped on that end user’s browser. The data gathered from these cookies will be used to help AdSense publishers better serve and manage the ads on their site(s) and across the web. [Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

**Questions / Input**

If you have questions or suggestions relating to your information, or wish to make a complaint, please contact us.

Without prejudice to any other rights you may have, you also have the right to file a complaint against us. You can also complain to the supervisory authority in the EU member state in which you are based.
